Sylvia Beach Papers, 1887-1966 (bulk 1920s-1950s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 7: Photographs, 1881-1969; 14.1 linear feet 20 boxes
  - Subseries 7A: Beach Family Photographs, 1894-1969; 2.0 boxes
    - Photographs: Helen Jerome Eddy, undated; Cannons of Hollywood.; Grenbeaux, Paul, 1919-2009; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Photographs: Frederic Beach Dennis, 1934-1960; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Photographs: By Frederic Beach Dennis, 1960-1961; portions of 2 boxes
      - Photographs: By Frederic Beach Dennis, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Oversized Photograph: By Frederic Beach Dennis, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Photographs: Frederic J. Dennis, 1930-1935; Martel-Howlett Studios.; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Photographs: Frederic S. Dennis, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Photographs: Marguerite Wood MacCoy (Cousin) and Family, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Photographs: Doctor Thomas J. Orbison (Cousin), undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Photographs: Emma Virgina Beach (Reverend Beach's Sister), undated; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Photographs: Agnes Orbison (Aunt) and Mrs. Beach, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Photographs: Beach Family Group Pictures, undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Photographs: Unidentified Family Members, undated; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Photographs: "The Manse" - 26 Library Place, Princeton, New Jersey, Home of the Beach Family, 1920s-1967; Steltzer, Ulli.; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Subseries 7B: Sylvia Beach and Shakespeare and Company Photographs, 1902-1964; 5.0 boxes
    This subseries consists of images of Sylvia Beach and her life in Paris from just before the founding of Shakespeare and Company until her death. Photographs include family and friends, notable literary figures, Adrienne Monnier, and events Sylvia Beach attended later in her life.
    This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    Original negatives and the works of certain photographers are restricted.
    Researchers should contact the estates of Man Ray, Gisèle Freund, Berenice Abbott and other copyrighted photographers present in the collection for information regarding copyrighted photographs.
    - Photograph: Sylvia Beach at Bourré, Loir-Et-Cher, circa 1902; 1.0 box (Folder 1)
    - Photograph: Sylvia Beach and Holly Beach, circa 1904; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Photographs and Negatives: Wartime and Travel, 1914-1919; portions of 2 boxes
      The original order of materials in these folders is no longer discernible, but includes the following individuals and locations: Sylvia, Cyprian, and Eleanor Beach in Spain (including Ronda), 1914-1916 (negatives likely date from only 1916); Sylvia and Cyprian Beach on a boat to Italy, 1915; Sylvia Beach with the Volontaires Agricoles in Touraine, Summer 1917; Sylvia and Holly Beach in Belgrade, Serbia with the Red Cross, 1919.
      - Photographs: Wartime and Travel, 1912-1919; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        Includes envelopes with handwritten notations about the images.
      - Negatives: Wartime and Travel, 1914-1919; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        Not all negatives in this folder are represented by prints.
    - Photographs: Palais-Royal Period, circa 1917; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Photographs and Negative: Sylvia Beach at Rue Dupuytren by Claude Cahun, 1919; Cahun, Claude, 1894-1954; portions of 2 boxes
      Hand-written notes attribute these images to "Lucie Schwobb" (proper spelling: Lucy Schwob; later: Claude Cahun). These prints may be related to other prints from Rue Dupuytren from the same year located in other folders in this subseries, and some may possibly be attributed to the same photographer.
      - Photographs: Sylvia Beach at Rue Dupuytren by Claude Cahun, undated; 4 folders (Folder 1-4)
        Includes an image of Charles Winzer.
      - Negative: Sylvia Beach at Rue Dupuytren by Claude Cahun, 1919; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Photographs and Negative: Sylvia Beach and Holly Beach at Rue Dupuytren, 1919; portions of 2 boxes
      These images may be related to other prints from Rue Dupuytren from the same year located in other folders in this subseries, and some may possibly be attributed to the same photographer.
      - Photographs: Sylvia Beach and Holly Beach at Rue Dupuytren, 1919; 1 item (Folder 5)
      - Negative: Sylvia Beach and Holly Beach at Rue Dupuytren, 1919; 1 item (Folder 4)
    - Photograph: Sylvia Beach, Holly Beach and Stephen Vincent Benét at Rue Dupuytren, 1919; Cahun, Claude, 1894-1954; Malherbe, Suzanne, 1892-1972; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      These prints may be related to other prints from Rue Dupuytren from the same year located in other folders in this subseries, and may possibly be attributed to the same photographer. A negative of an image in this folder is present in Original Negatives: At Rue Dupuytren.
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach at Rue Dupuytren, 1919-1920; Alliance Film Service.; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Photographs and Negatives: Sylvia Beach and James Joyce at Shakespeare and Company, 1920-1922; portions of 2 boxes
      Includes an image of John Rodker. Dates written on back of prints appear to conflict; some images taken at the same time (based on visual information in images) are labeled with different years. Sylvia Beach and James Joyce are pictured at both locations of Shakespeare and Company. Includes Sylvia with Ulysses. Includes a glass-plate negative.
      - Photographs: Sylvia Beach and James Joyce at Shakespeare and Company, 1920-1922; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Negatives: Sylvia Beach and James Joyce at Shakespeare and Company, 1920-1922; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        Includes a glass plate negative. Please be careful as it is extremely fragile.
    - Photograph of a Painting: Sylvia Beach By Paul-Émile Bécat, 1923; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach, circa 1923; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach by Berenice Abbott, 1926; portions of 2 boxes
      - Portrait: Sylvia Beach Seated at Desk by Berenice Abbott, 1926; 1; portion of 1 folder (11.25 x 8.5 inches) (Folder 5)
        Signed "B. Abbott, Paris 1926" on recto.
      - Formal portrait: Sylvia Beach by Berenice Abbott, 1926; 1; 1 signed photograph portion of 1 folder Signed "Abbott—Paris—1926" on recto. (Folder 6)
      - Copy Prints: Sylvia Beach by Berenice Abbott, 1926; 2; 5 copy prints portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Photographs: Reverend Sylvester Beach Outside Shakespeare and Company, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Photographs: Passport Photograph, 1929; Delbo, P.; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Photograph: Sylvia Beach With Henry Festing Jones, 1920s; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach by Man Ray, undated; portions of 2 boxes
      - Formal Portrait: Sylvia Beach Looking Right by Man Ray, undated; 6; Man Ray, 1890-1976; 1.0 folder (5.5 x 3.5 inches (mounted in frame 14.5 x 11.5)) (Folder 7)
      - Copy Prints: Sylvia Beach Looking Right by Man Ray, undated; 1; Man Ray, 1890-1976; 2 copy prints (6.25 x 4.25 inches) (Folder 7)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach by Henri Martinie, 1920s; Martinie, A.-H. (A.-Henri), b. 1881; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Photographs and Negatives: Sylvia Beach and Others Outside Shakespeare and Company, 1920s; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      Includes Myrsine Moschos and Madame Tisserand.
    - Photographs and Negative: Street Views of Rue De L'Odéon, 1920s-1930s; portions of 2 boxes
      - Photographs: Street Views of Rue De L'Odéon, 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - Negative: Street Views of Rue De L'Odéon, 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Photographs and Negative: Sylvia Beach in Shakespeare and Company, 1931 December; Condé Nast Publications, inc..; portions of 2 boxes
      - Photographs: Sylvia Beach in Shakespeare and Company, 1931 December; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Glass-Plate Negative: Sylvia Beach in Shakespeare and Company, 1931 December; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        Please be extremely careful with the glass-plate negative as it is very fragile.
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach and Jane Van Meter by Studio Harcourt, 1934-1935; Studio Harcourt.; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Photograph: Sylvia Beach in Normandy, 1936 July; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      Photograph stamped "Le Capitaine" with signature.
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach by Gisèle Freund, 1930s; 2 folders
      - Formal Portrait: Sylvia Beach Looking Right by Gisèle Freund, 1930s; 1; Freund, Gisèle; 1 photograph portion of 1 folder (10 x 7 inches) (Folder 10)
        Stamped on reverse "Please Credit Gisèle Freund, 12, Rue Lalande, Paris-XIV"
      - Portrait: Sylvia Beach With Cigarette by Gisèle Freund, 1930s; 2; Freund, Gisèle; 5 prints of 2 images portion of 1 folder (7 x 9 inches) (Folder 10)
        Stamped on reverse "Gisèle Freund, 18, Rue de l’Odéon, Paris." Some prints are cropped.
      - Snapshot: Sylvia Beach Stepping off a Plane by Gisèle Freund, 1936 March; 1; Freund, Gisèle; portion of 1 folder (4 x 2.5 inches) (Folder 11)
        Written on reverse "SB back from London, March 1936, photo by Gisèle"
      - Snapshots: Standing in Front of Shakespeare and Company With Adrienne Monnier and Virgina Pfeiffer by Gisèle Freund, 1936; 2; Freund, Gisèle; 6 photographic prints of 3 images portion of 1 folder (5 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 11)
        Multiple views and multiple prints of the same occasion. A few have hand-written notes on the verso that say similar things. One written on reverse "Adrienne à la porte de Shakespeare and Company avec Sylvia et Virginia Pfeiffer (Hemingway’s sister-in-law)"
      - Snapshot: Sylvia Beach Standing in Front of Shakespeare and Company With Margaret Newitt by Gisèle Freund, 1936; 4; Freund, Gisèle; portion of 1 folder (4.5 x 7 inches) (Folder 11)
        Written on reverse "1936, Margaret Newit," stamped on reverse "Please credit Gisèle Freund, 12 rue Lalande, Paris-XIV"
      - Snapshot: Sylvia Beach Standing on a Stepladder in Front of Shakespeare and Company by Gisèle Freund, 1936; 5; Freund, Gisèle; portion of 1 folder (10 x 6.5 inches) (Folder 11)
      - Formal Portraits: Sylvia Beach in Shakespeare and Company by Gisèle Freund, 1936; 6; Freund, Gisèle; 14 prints of 5 images portion of 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Photographs and Negatives: Sylvia Beach, Margaret Newitt, And Others Outside Shakespeare and Company, 1936; portions of 2 boxes
      - Photographs: Margaret Newitt and Others Outside Shakespeare and Company, 1936; 5 photographs (Folder 20)
        The photographs present in this folder (and their corresponding negatives) are of two different sizes, but appear to have been taken on the same occasion. The prints in this folder represent only a few of the negatives corresponding to this occasion.
      - Negatives: Sylvia Beach, Margaret Newitt, And Others Outside Shakespeare and Company, 1936; 15 negatives (Folder 12)
        Some negatives present in this folder (and their corresponding prints) are of two different sizes, but appear to have been taken on the same occasion. Not all of these negatives exist as prints.
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach Visiting Family in California, 1936; 1 folder (Folder 21)
      Formerly attributed to photographer Gisele Freud for reasons unknown. Includes Sylvia with her father and nephew.
    - Photographs and Negatives: Sylvia Beach by Lore Kohlberg, circa 1936; Kohlberg, Lore; portions of 2 boxes
      - Photographs: Sylvia Beach by Lore Kohlberg, circa 1936; 1 folder (Folder 22)
      - Negatives: Sylvia Beach by Lore Kohlberg, circa 1936; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach and Adrienne Monnier in Shakespeare and Company for the New York Times, circa 1936; 1 folder (Folder 23)
      Stamped "The New York Times S.A. / Wide World Photos"
    - Photographs and Negatives: Priscilla Curtis at Shakespeare and Company, circa 1937; portions of 2 boxes
      - Photographs: Priscilla Curtis at Shakespeare and Company, circa 1937; 1 folder (Folder 24)
      - Negatives: Priscilla Curtis at Shakespeare and Company, circa 1937; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach by International News Photos, 1938; International News Photos (New York, N.Y.).; 1 folder (Folder 25)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach, James Joyce, And Adrienne Monnier by Gisèle Freund, 1938; Freund, Gisèle; 1 folder
      - Group Portrait: Sylvia Beach Laughing With James Joyce and Adrienne Monnier by Gisèle Freund, 1938; Freund, Gisèle; 1 item (Folder 15)
        Verso includes Gisèle Freund stamp.
      - Inscribed Group Portrait: Sylvia Beach With James Joyce and Adrienne Monnier by Gisèle Freund, 1938; 1 item (Folder 15)
        Faint inscription on recto of print reads: "To Howard C. Rice, with my thanks and kind regards, Gisèle." Verso includes Gisèle Freund stamp, and hand-written notes including: "James Joyce with his two publishers inside the bookshop "Shakespeare and Co" rue d'Odeon in Paris, 1938."
      - Group Portrait: Sylvia Beach With James Joyce and Adrienne Monnier by Gisèle Freund, 1938; 1 item (Folder 15)
        Shakespeare and Comapny stamp on verso, and note: "James Joyce Sylvia Beach Adrienne Monnier par Gisèle Freund."
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach, circa 1938; 1 folder (Folder 26)
      Two formal portraits by "F Deibo" or "F Deibc."
    - Negatives: Sylvia Beach by Thérèse Bonney, 1930s; Bonney, Thérèse, 1894-1978; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Photograph: "Réunion De Mesures ", 1930s; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      Note attached to image reads: Réunion de MESURES chez Henry Church, Fondaleur de la revue, à Ville d'Auray. Henri Michaux, Adrienne Monnier, Sylvia Beach, Germaine Paulhan, Michel Leiris, Henry Church, Audiberti, Barbara Church, Jean Paulhan.
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach by Eliane Janet Le Caisne, 1930s; Janet Le Caisne, Eliane; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Photographs: Wartime, 1940-1944; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Photographs and Negatives: Marcelle Fournier and Cats at Foyer Des Etudiants, 1943; portions of 2 boxes
      Likely taken in and around the small roof-top apartment where Sylvia Beach hid after being released from the internment camp at Vittel in Spring 1943. Located at 93, Boulevard de Saint-Michel.
      - Photographs: Marcelle Fournier and Cats at Foyer Des Etudiants, 1943; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Negatives: Marcelle Fournier and Cats at Foyer Des Etudiants, 1943; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Photographs: The Liberation of Paris, 1944 August; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach and Friends After the Liberation For LIFE Magazine, 1944; Scherman, David E., (David Edward), 1916-1997; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Includes images of a party with writer Yvonne Desvignes, writer Max-Pol Fouchet, writer and Resistance fighter Jean Marcel Bruller (Vercors), American diplomat Keeler Faus, journalist Jean Schlumberger, Paul Valéry, Jean Denoël, André Chamson, Jean Paulhan, Adrienne Monnier, Marie Monnier, Henri Michaux, Ernest Hemingway, and war correspondent Helen Kirkpatrick (not all individuals pictured). An image in this file appeared in LIFE Magazine on April 10, 1964. An image from the same event appeared November 8, 1954. Folder includes correspondence with Elmer W. Lower of Time and LIFE Ltd. dated 1945 March 27. See also: Hemingway, Ernest for related photographs.
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach Visits the Ruined Hotel Corneille After Liberation, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach After the Liberation of Paris for the New York Times, 1945; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach by Richard Wright, 1946; Wright, Richard, 1908-1960; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach at James Joyce's Grave by Camilla Steinbrugge, 1951 December; 1.0 folder (Folder 10)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach While Visiting New York and Connecticut, 1956; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach With Arthur Harold Moss, 1958; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Photograph: Sylvia Beach Receiving Honorary Degree at the University of Buffalo, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach at Unidentified Country Home, circa 1959; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach Attending "Paris in the Twenties", 1960 June; Chaptel, A.; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      At the USIS Gallery. Includes Harriet Weaver, Jane Cody, David Wright, John Bodley, Catherine Gide, and others.
    - Photograph: Sylvia Beach by Henri Cartier-Bresson, 1960; 1; Cartier-Bresson, Henri, 1908-2004; 1.0 folder (11.5 x 8 inches) (Folder 18)
      Formal portrait Sylvia Beach in front of picture of Shakespeare. Inscribed on reverse "avec mon très respectueuse souvenir, Henri Cartier-Bresson," stamped on reverse "Complimentary print, not to be reproduced without written permission of magnum photos, 125 Faubourg Saint-Honoré, Paris-VIII"
    - Photograph of a Drawing: Sylvia Beach by Desmond Harmsworth, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach and Carlotta Briggs and Family at Bourré, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Portrait Photographs: Sylvia Beach by Johannes Skancke Martens, 1961 November; Martens, Johannes Skancke; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Photographs and Negatives: Trip to Greece and Egypt, 1961; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      Snapshots of a trip with Yves Bonnefoy, Marthiel and Jackson Mathews.
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach by Photo Pic, circa 1961; Photo Pic.; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach at the Dedication of the James Joyce Tower and Museum, 1962 June 16; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - Screencaptures: "An Appointment With Sylvia Beach" From Maurice Saillet, 1962 August 6; 10 photographs 4 negatives 1 envelope (Folder 22)
      Consists of photographs of a television screen with Sylvia Beach appearing on "Appointment with Sylvia Beach" with Malcolm Muggeridge.
    - Photographs: Sylvia Beach's Grave by H. C. Rice, 1964; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - Negatives: Sylvia Beach in Nice, undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Subseries 7C: Adrienne Monnier and La Maison Des Amis De Livres Photographs, 1910-1959; 3.0 boxes
    This subseries consists of images of Adrienne Monnier and her lending library Les Amis.
    - Photographs and Negative: Adrienne Monnier, 1910s-1950s; portions of 2 boxes
      Contains various portraits and snapshots (most undated) of Adrienne Monnier in Paris. One image copyrighted by The New York Times.
      - Photographs: Adrienne Monnier, 1910s-1950s; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Negative: Adrienne Monnier, circa 1927; 1 negative (Folder 20)
        Negative of a snapshot of Adrienne Monnier and dog Teddy in Rue de L'Odéon. Print is present in folder Photographs: Adrienne Monnier.
    - Photograph: Sylvia Beach and Adrienne Monnier Holding Poster For "Biblioteque Particuliere D’Adrienne Monnier" By Berenice Abbott, 1926; 1; Abbott, Berenice, 1898-1991; 1.0 folder (3.75 x 5.75 inches) (Folder 21)
    - Photograph: Adrienne Monnier Standing Portrait by Berenice Abbott, 1926; Abbott, Berenice, 1898-1991; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Photographs and Negative: Friends of La Maison Des Amis De Livres Photographs, 1920s; portions of 2 boxes
      - Photographs: Friends of La Maison Des Amis De Livres Photographs, 1920s; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Negatives: Friends of La Maison Des Amis De Livres Photographs, 1920s; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - Oversized Photographs: Formal Portraits of Adrienne Monnier, 1920-1929; Manuel, Henri; more than 3 folders
      - Formal Portraits: Adrienne Monnier by Henri Martinie, 1920s; Martinie, A.-H. (A.-Henri), b. 1881; 2 folders (Folder 2-3)
      - Formal Portrait: Adrienne Monnier by Eliane Janet Le Caisne, 1920s; Janet Le Caisne, Eliane; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        Signed by the photographer.
      - Photomontage: Adrienne Monnier, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        A photographic image consisting of many photographs combined. The central image is a reproduction of a portrait of Adrienne Monnier by Eliane Janet Le Caisne.
    - Photographs: Adrienne Monnier by Henri Manuel, 1932; Manuel, Henri; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Photographs: Adrienne Monnier and Maurice Saillet by Jean-Marie Marcel, 1946; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      Includes an unknown individual.
    - Photograph of a Painting: Adrienne Monnier by Paul-Émile Bécat, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Photographs: Adrienne Monnier by Gisèle Freund, 1920-1954; portions of 2 boxes
      See also Beach, Sylvia with James Joyce and Adrienne Monnier, Box 277, Folder 8.
      - Portrait: Adrienne Monnier Seated and Reading by Gisèle Freund, undated; 1; Freund, Gisèle; portion of 1 folder (5.5 x 4 inches) (Folder 23)
        Stamped on reverse "Copyright Foto Gisèle Freund, Tres Sargentos 436, Buenos Aires"
      - Portrait: Adrienne Monnier Seated and Reading in 18 Rue De L'Odéon by Gisèle Freund, undated; Freund, Gisèle; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Portrait: Adrienne Monnier in Doorway by Gisèle Freund, undated; 1 folder (11 x 15.5 inches) (Folder 1)
      - Portrait: Adrienne Monnier in Profile by Gisèle Freund, undated; 2; Freund, Gisèle; 2 vintage photographic postards 1 larger copy print portion of 1 folder (5.5 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 23)
      - Portrait: Adrienne Monnier Standing at Bookshelves by Gisèle Freund, undated; 3; Freund, Gisèle; 2 stamped copies portion of 1 folder (6.5 x 9.5 inches) (Folder 23)
        Inscribed on reverse "Adrienne Monnier dans la librairie, a 7 rue de l’Odéon," stamped on reverse "Copyright by Gisèle Freund, All rights reserved."
      - Portrait: Adrienne Monnier Standing at Bookshelves by Gisèle Freund, undated; Freund, Gisèle; 1 matted print (Folder 2)
      - Formal Portrait: Adrienne Monnier in Profile by Gisèle Freund, undated; 4; Freund, Gisèle; portion of 1 folder (6.5 x 9 inches (on card 9 x 11.5)) (Folder 23)
        Initialed G. F., stamped on reverse "Gisèle Freund, 18, Rue de l’Odéon, Paris"
      - Portrait: Adrienne Monnier Buying Fruit at a Market by Gisèle Freund, 1938; 5; Freund, Gisèle; portion of 1 folder (6.5 x 10 inches) (Folder 23)
        Signed Gisèle Freund, stamped on reverse "Copyright by Gisèle Freund, All rights reserved."
      - Snapshots: Adrienne Monnier Signing a Book by Gisèle Freund, 1953-1954; 6; Freund, Gisèle; 2 images portion of 1 folder (4.5 x 7 inches) (Folder 23)
        "Photo Gisèle Freund" written on reverse.
      - Snapshots: Adrienne Monnier Sitting at Desk Speaking to Two Men by Gisèle Freund, 1953-1954; 8; Freund, Gisèle; 3 images portion of 1 folder (5 x 7 inches) (Folder 23)
        Inscribed "photo Gisèle Freund"
      - Portrait: Adrienne Monnier Standing in Front of Shakespeare and Company by Gisèle Freund, 1920s; 10; Freund, Gisèle; 2 vintage stamped prints and 1 larger copy print portion of 1 folder (6.75 x 9 inches) (Folder 23)
        Stamped on reverse "Copyright Gisela Freund"
      - Portrait: Adrienne Monnier Standing in Front of Shakespeare and Company by Gisèle Freund, 1920s; Freund, Gisèle; 1 matted print (Folder 3)
    - Photographs: Unidentified Photographs Related to Adrienne Monnier, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Original context implies these unknown individuals were associated with Adrienne Monnier and her family.
    - Notes and Lists: On Photographs by and of Adrienne Monnier, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      Consists of envelopes with handwritten notations. Also contains a detailed list of photographs labeled "Photos à Adrienne et d'Adrienne" with details about photographs now located in various folders in this collection.
  - Subseries 7D: Sylvia Beach and Adrienne Monnier Personal and Family Photographs, 1890-1969; 3 boxes (2 partial)